<artifact id="proposal" change="refactor-widget-granularity" schema="spec-driven">

<task>
Create the proposal artifact for change "refactor-widget-granularity".
Initial proposal document outlining the change
</task>

<project_context>
<!-- This is background information for you. Do NOT include this in your output. -->
Language: Portuguese (pt-BR)
All artifacts must be written in Brazilian Portuguese.
</project_context>

<output>
Write to: D:\financorp\openspec\changes\refactor-widget-granularity\proposal.md
</output>

<instruction>
Create the proposal document that establishes WHY this change is needed.

Sections:
- **Why**: 1-2 sentences on the problem or opportunity. What problem does this solve? Why now?
- **What Changes**: Bullet list of changes. Be specific about new capabilities, modifications, or removals. Mark breaking changes with **BREAKING**.
- **Capabilities**: Identify which specs will be created or modified:
  - **New Capabilities**: List capabilities being introduced. Each becomes a new `specs/<name>/spec.md`. Use kebab-case names (e.g., `user-auth`, `data-export`).
  - **Modified Capabilities**: List existing capabilities whose REQUIREMENTS are changing. Only include if spec-level behavior changes (not just implementation details). Each needs a delta spec file. Check `openspec/specs/` for existing spec names. Leave empty if no requirement changes.
- **Impact**: Affected code, APIs, dependencies, or systems.

IMPORTANT: The Capabilities section is critical. It creates the contract between
proposal and specs phases. Research existing specs before filling this in.
Each capability listed here will need a corresponding spec file.

Keep it concise (1-2 pages). Focus on the "why" not the "how" -
implementation details belong in design.md.

This is the foundation - specs, design, and tasks all build on this.
</instruction>

<template>
<!-- Use this as the structure for your output file. Fill in the sections. -->
## Why

<!-- Explain the motivation for this change. What problem does this solve? Why now? -->

## What Changes

<!-- Describe what will change. Be specific about new capabilities, modifications, or removals. -->

## Capabilities

### New Capabilities
<!-- Capabilities being introduced. Replace <name> with kebab-case identifier (e.g., user-auth, data-export, api-rate-limiting). Each creates specs/<name>/spec.md -->
- `<name>`: <brief description of what this capability covers>

### Modified Capabilities
<!-- Existing capabilities whose REQUIREMENTS are changing (not just implementation).
     Only list here if spec-level behavior changes. Each needs a delta spec file.
     Use existing spec names from openspec/specs/. Leave empty if no requirement changes. -->
- `<existing-name>`: <what requirement is changing>

## Impact

<!-- Affected code, APIs, dependencies, systems -->
</template>

<success_criteria>
<!-- To be defined in schema validation rules -->
</success_criteria>

<unlocks>
Completing this artifact enables: design, specs
</unlocks>

</artifact>
